[Music]
welcome back to am Northwest you know
if you're planning a garage sale anytime
soon you'll want to get some expert tips
and we've got just the person for you
we welcome back Gary GMA and T appraiser
good to see you again thanks having me
in okay so let's first start though with
the difference between a garage sale
and say an estate sale because they are
different right they are well they're
basically the same idea it's more a matter
of size a garage sale uh people have
cleaned out their house and are getting
rid of all the junk they don't want
right right and a state sale or a
downsizing sale usually means somebody their
Pastor is moving and they're getting
rid of everything in the house and so
people dealers especially want to go
to the estate sales because there's a
bigger chance of finding something that
they might be able to resell I always
think of estate sales as usually higher
end stuff it can be but it's all it's
all the stuff it isn't just people are
going to give away anyway so so if you're
running a garage sale don't advertise it
as an estate sale you'll get people mad
at you good point good point Okay so when
you you also talked too about setting
up your sale to look like Nordstoms yes
you want it you want it to look as good
as possible there's a reason marketing
uh department stores do what they do
uh and if you don't clean it if you
don't polish it if you don't make it look
good why would someone pay any money for
it oh right okay so you want it to look
just as nice and presented and then
work for displays like here it can be
something simple like we did I just
have a couple of old boxes and we put a
tablecloth on it and you get right as
opposed of it just being a bunch of stuff
flat on the table breaks your eye makes
it more interesting and then as things
sell you keep fluffing it back up so it
all looks fresh okay and then let's talk
about signage because that's huge I
think it is it is when it comes to your
marketing about 80% of the people or more
come to your sale because they saw the
sign right I don't believe in subtle signs
you know I had I had a I had a GU who
work from years ago she'd do a white
board and you A Thin Blue Line and no one
could read it I want to be able to see
it blocks away because especially if
you're coming off of a busy street into
your neighborhood they need to make that
decision way ahead and if they pass by
often times they're not going to turn
around and come back so good signs that
are consistent just simple don't put
your life story on it just estate sale
garage sale whatever you're running and
an arrow come this way and people will
it'll just bring them right in people
will drive by and if they see something
kind of even in the car they'll stop and
in the middle of the sale if things slow
way down you wonder why it means your
signs have blown down so send some somebody
out in the car send your kid out in
the car to go look at the signs and
put them back up you really do have
experiences send the kid out to go look
at the signs all right ads taking out
ads are really important ads can be
important especially if you have an estate
of some really great things and it's so
cheap Craigslist next door offer up they
they come up with a new one every time
but make sure you put photos in of your
key items don't put everything in but
some really great items that make people
want to come right if you want if you
have a really big sale and you want to pay
for an ad aate statale finder.com is
the local one to use and they put ads it
cost you 20 bucks I think 25 I can't
remember now but uh it's not huge money but
that's where all the dealers look to
see which sales they want to go to I
stopped at a garage sale the other day
and I thought what was really really
smart of the person to do was anything
that had to be plugged in was plugged in
so people see if it could work or not
absolutely and that's also placed the idea
of of look at your room if you're in
a garage and it's dark you need to put
lights in so people can see have music
playing yeah oh smart have that light
jazz something that makes people because
people feel funny if in an echo chamber
whispering to their friend if they want
to buy this they don't want the person
to selling to hear it right and so and
it makes you feel upbeat and if you're
happy in a clean happy Place full of
fun stuff you're going to spend money I
like it bartering what are your thoughts
on bartering um okay when it comes to
having a sale you want to have it either
a two or three day sale I do three-day
sales okay Thursday Friday Saturday do
not have your sale on a Sunday because
the world is shifted it used to be in
miltown that was your weekend off now
everyone works different hours buyers
come Thursday and Friday Lookers come on
Saturday oh you might even consider one
thing a lot of the professionals do is
the uh the night before the last day is
to move things around and put your most
valuable things together and then
everything else is half price $50 and under
is half price okay blows it out
and then the last um hour or two
follow the advice that great Portland uh
Founding Father Tom Peterson free is a
very good price and so at at the very end
it's free and you don't have to box it
up and take it to Goodwill it's gone
there you go there you go now talk to me
about price tags I think everything
should be priced clearly and the tag
appropriate to the size of the item
you want it to be clear and ideally on
expensive things put down what it is
so book ends or BL because it will uh
people switch tags yeah and so you want
to use the right size tags go and spend
a few bucks don't get those dots that say
25 C you know I've done that I've done
that okay yeah I thought a big rule that
is very important for everyone to keep
in mind is never let anybody inside your
house right right never let the there's
all kinds of reasons they may try to
don't do that um so don't leave your door
unlocked make sure everything's shut
always have two people you and a friend
yeah you know so you can't get distracted
and they take your till uh if you end
up with a bunch of money if noon or 1:00
you realize take the bulk of the money
hide it in the house never have more than
a hundred bucks yeah and also you want
you say though to have change for people
definitely have change I always say
don't price anything in less than 50
cents and in increments of 50 cents that
way if you go half price it's easy math
and um um you only have to have quarters
ones quart fives ones and quarters to
start with to make the change and lastly
you say if you don't sell it bless it or
if you sell something for less than you
would hope for bless it and give it out
absolutely and and you're going to make
mistakes relax you're going to sell
something way too cheap and you're going to
find out about it a year later when the
neighbor's bragging about what he got
for it right bless him anyway you know
it served its purpose for you you'll end
up your goal is to end up with an empty
garage some money in your pocket and
Marie condo smiling on you I love it I
love it all right we're going to put all
those tips on our website at k2.com
thank you so much I will'll be right back
with more am Northwest don't go away
[Music]